foreign
to the mountains of my home in the
pursuit of a very Noble flower it is
known as the Wild Tiger Lily also the
Oregon Lily the Columbia Lily it goes by
many names
lilies are social flowers they like to
grow in small groups if there are too
many of them in one place they may get
crowded but with a few close friends
they flourish I can relate to these
lilies I feel at my best around family
members and choice friends I'm not a
social butterfly neither am I
disconnected I'm somewhere in between
and I like it that way
[Music]
embracing connection was the antidote to
the loneliness I felt years ago and I
find that not only humans but animals in
nature provide that source of friendship
and speaking of friendship I decided to
go visit a very special person today
[Music]
I took pictures of the lilies I found to
an artist who has mastered
silversmithing her name is Nicole and
she makes absolutely enchanting
creations
[Music]
foreign
as she worked she allowed me to watch
her process as well as sneak away for a
few moments to explore the wonders of
her magical Studio I loved spending time
with another creative soul and couldn't
have been happier with the result if
you'd like to see more of her work I
will leave information down below as she
makes amazing jewelry as well as art
pieces
five ten minutes
[Music]
foreign
as she worked Nicole told me her story
how she always wanted to dedicate time
to her art and was very passionate about
nature and conservation and how
eventually she found a way to start her
own business it was inspiring to see
someone who just kept working towards
their dreams no matter what even when it
took a long time and there were setbacks
along the way what a wonderful reminder
that we can all make our dreams happen
though it may materialize in a way we
did not anticipate or on a timeline we
did not plan
thank you
[Music]
foreign
I spent most of the day away from home
and didn't return until the sun was
setting and I was quite hungry my new
art piece inspired me to make a meal
using the daylilies growing in the
garden
fried buds taste like buttery delicious
vegetables and paired well with a
coconut curry using some peppers and
beans from both my garden and the
grocery store
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
as I've gotten healthier cooking has
become an increasingly enjoyable process
this morning I made oatmeal with butter
banana honey and cinnamon for lunch I
had cream cheese bagels with sprouts and
tofu I try to cook and eat quietly
focusing on the motions and preparing my
food as well as consuming it it was an
important part in healing my
relationship with what I eat
[Music]
foreign
at the end of the day I've rather
self-critical in negative thoughts and
those are always a reminder to me to
practice joy and respond to how I feel
with encouragement focusing on a more
empowering mindset that helps me
remember that this day was full of so
many blessings everything from lilies to
Art and a good meal to a shelter to come
home to it was a beautiful day and I
wish the same for you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
I have been absolutely mesmerized by
this piece I have never worked with
metal or done anything related to
jewelry and it was so incredible to see
her work and I actually picked some
daylilies this morning
and I realize now
that they look so similar don't they
look beautiful there are so many lilies
growing around the valley right now
there are tiger lilies there's Glacier
lilies you know just all sorts of
beautiful flowers it got me thinking
about how I think that all of us have a
creative side to who we are you know if
we are able to kind of uh be open to
that Nicole actually does a extremely
unique style of silversmithing she makes
all of these things by hand she does not
use molds she is definitely a kind of
groundbreaking in her approach to
working with these Metals so I will
share all of her links Down Below in
case you're interested in learning more
about her and I thought I would use this
as a moment to talk about something that
has been hard for me since I have
started this channel whenever you put
your art out into the world you get
mixed reactions when I started making
videos which to me this is an art form
but also sharing my own art I got a
positive reviews as well as criticism
and when I first started that was hard
to take it was hard to hear people
saying that they really didn't enjoy
what you were doing and what you were
putting out or that they didn't even
think you should be allowed to put
things out into the world and it is
never easy to take criticism but
whenever I think of art that kind of
comes to mind because I think the whole
point of art is for it not to be about
how other people react and what other
people say or do it is about your own
personal journey and your own
relationship with what you're doing I
hope this Lily can encourage all of you
to make sure you put people's feedback
in a healthy place to not over use it in
terms of defining who you are and
whether or not you should try new things
or put yourself out there you know it
really is up to you at the end of the
day and I think we all stand in our own
way way more than we would like to admit
sometimes and it is so important to be
aware of that and push ourselves a
little bit out of our comfort zone now
and then I think it is probably good for
us all at least it is good for me well I
think I might have to go back up to the
mountains now and see if I can find some
glacial lilies to compare this to be
true to who you are this week enjoy your
own creative side enjoy the parts of you
that other people might think are odd or
strange or weird I have been called
strange weird childish I've been called
so many things and if I internalized all
those words I wouldn't be able to keep
doing this and it is so important to
know who you are and to know that your
innate worth is already here no matter
what in the same way that Nicole and I
like to put our art out into the world I
hope you put your own self out to the
world and your own creativity and all
its shapes and forms and don't be too
afraid to have courage and be kind my
favorite princess quote forever and ever
thank you for all the support of my Etsy
shop and my own work as an artist it
means the world please feel free to show
Nicole some support as well again all
her links are down below you can connect
with her she is an incredible person so
I'm so fortunate to have met her sending
you so much love and I will see you
again very soon goodbye
foreign
[Music]